welcome to another tutorial in this
欢迎使用本教程中的另一个教程
video we're going to be playing with the
我们将要播放的视频是
Dodge and burn and these smudge tools
减淡和烧录以及这些涂抹工具
and learning about some of the different
并了解一些不同的
options getting a little bit more
选项变得更多
familiar with using these tools and
熟悉使用这些工具和
we're going to be working with an actual
我们将与一位真正的
photograph this time so I'm gonna go to
这次拍照 所以我要去
file and go to open you can choose any
文件 然后打开 您可以选择任何
photograph I'm just navigated to some
照片我只是浏览到了一些
pictures that I have here on my computer
我电脑里的照片
and so yours will be different but I'm
所以你的会有所不同 但我
going to select this image here and one
我要在这里选择这张图片和一张
common thing that's going to happen when
这是一件很常见的事情 当
you go to open an image is sometimes
你去打开一个图像有时是这样的
it'll be a different color profile this
这将是一个不同的颜色配置文件
really doesn't matter at this point in
在这一点上真的不重要
time you can either say keep or convert
时间 你可以说保留或转换
this is just saying this has an sRGB
这只是说这有一个sRGB
color profile and it's wondering if I'd
颜色档案 它想知道我是否
like to use the built-in srgb and
我喜欢使用内置的sRGB和
so I'm just gonna say keep in this case
所以我只想说 在这种情况下
sometimes you may want to convert but
有时你可能想皈依 但
don't worry about that for now it's just
别担心 现在只是
how interprets the colors in the
中的颜色如何解释
image
图像
so this is I think in darktable earlier
这是我之前在暗版中想到的
this is a kind of an edited photo but
这是一张经过编辑的照片 但
we'll play with a smudge tool if we left
如果我们离开了 我们会玩涂抹工具
click on smudge like the shortcut is s
点击涂抹 就像快捷方式是S
to access this tool and it's very very
访问这个工具 它是非常非常
small right now so I may bring up the
现在很小 所以我可以把
size by just using my scroll wheel or
只需使用滚轮或
left clicking and dragging up this size
左键单击并向上拖动此大小
to get to something larger and we can
为了获得更大的成就 我们可以
see what the smudge will let us do if i
看看污点会让我们做什么 如果我
zoom in here it'll just sort of smudge
放大这里 它只会有点模糊
and soften up these clouds quite a bit
使这些云层变得柔和一些
actually I can kind of mix its you can
事实上 我可以混合它 你可以
almost imagine the ink of this picture
几乎可以想象这幅画的墨水
is still wet and so I'm just smudging it
仍然是湿的 所以我只是弄脏它
I'm smudging these clouds I'm just left
我在涂抹这些云彩 我只剩下
clicking and holding to create sort of
点击并按住以创建一种
this smudge so you can by hand sort of
这个污点 这样你就可以用手
come in here and create a different kind
来这里 创造一种不同的
of effect I suppose you could smudge out
我想你可以用涂抹的方式
all the edges to create sort of a little
所有的边缘都创造了一点
vignette a little smudge vignette in or
在或中有一点模糊的小插曲
something around the image if ever we
图像周围的一些东西 如果我们曾经
get to a point again that we don't
再说一次 我们没有
really like what we've done we can hit
真的很喜欢我们所做的 我们可以
ctrl Z on the keyboard to undo some of
按住键盘上的Ctrl Z键可撤消某些操作
that there's also some other options we
我们还有一些其他的选择
can play with besides just size and we
除了大小 我们还可以玩
haven't really done much of these but we
我还没有真正做过这些 但我们
have aspect ratio which is going to be
其纵横比将是
more of like we can make our brush size
更像是我们可以把画笔的大小
a more oval like
更像是椭圆形的
if we're trying to fit it in a certain
如果我们想把它放在某个特定的位置
area we can adjust the angle so now we
我们可以调整角度 所以现在我们
have this an oval here that's sort of at
在这里有一个椭圆形 有点像是
an angle so we can play with those and
一个角度 这样我们就可以玩这些
we've learned in the past we can just
我们在过去学到了 我们可以
click this button here to reset these
单击此处可重置这些设置
back to default if we don't like what
如果我们不喜欢什么 就返回默认设置
we've done we don't like the changes
我们已经做了 我们不喜欢这些变化
that we've made to the brush itself and
我们对刷子本身所做的
then but these are all similar if you
那么这些都是相似的
notice if we went to the pencil tool or
请注意 如果我们使用铅笔工具或
the brush tool these all have the same
画笔工具都是一样的
option size angle aspect ratio so smudge
选项大小角度纵横比如此模糊
is going to have those same options but
也会有同样的选择 但
it also has some different options down
它还有一些不同的选项可供选择
below we have this apply jitter which
下面我们有这个应用抖动 它
will kind of randomly it doesn't make a
会有点随机 它不会让一个
big difference in this case but you we
在这种情况下有很大的不同 但你我们
can we can turn this up any time you're
我们可以随时调高音量吗？
not sure what something does I'll turn
不知道我会变成什么样子
the amount way up and see if I notice a
金额一直在上升 看看我是否注意到
difference so in this case can you see
不同的是 在这种情况下 你能看到
what's happening as I do this it's
我做这件事的时候发生了什么
creating these dots all over it's kind
把这些点画得到处都是真是太好了
of a jitter outside of even my brush and
甚至在我的刷子外面都有抖动
so you turn that down
所以你拒绝了那个
but the jitter just sort of applies it
但抖动在某种程度上应用了它
instead of doing it at one location it
它不是在一个地方做 而是
sort of randomly applies it around and
就像是随机地在周围使用它
again this is the smudge tool but
同样 这是涂抹工具 但是
different tools have a jitter as well we
不同的工具也有抖动 我们
can apply it to different things let's
可以把它应用于不同的事情 让我们
look at the dodging burn so if we go I
看着闪避的灼伤 如果我们走了
mean ctrl Z and undo some of that that I
我的意思是按Ctrl Z键并取消其中的一部分
did there and oh I want to show you one
有吗？哦 我想给你看一个
other way to to bring an image in maybe
另一种方式可能会带来一幅图像
we want to close this we can click this
我们想关闭此窗口 可以点击此按钮
X up here and just say discard changes
X在这里 然后只说放弃更改
so we won't save any of that we can also
所以我们不会保存任何我们也可以
navigate to a location on our computer
导航到我们计算机上的某个位置
I'll go to these same images and I'll
我会去看这些相同的图片 我会
just drag in this image here we'll
只需将这张图像拖入此处 我们将
left-click and drag it into and
左键单击并将其拖动到和中
again we can either keep or convert this
同样 我们可以保留或转换这一点
time I guess I'll say convert and so we
时间到了 我想我会说皈依 所以我们
have this image and we can do this Dodge
有了这张图片 我们就可以进行这种躲避
and burn if we select the Dodge and burn
如果我们选择道奇并烧毁 则烧毁
tool it's shift D is the shortcut to
工具的Shift D键是进入
access the Dodge and burn tool and what
访问减淡和刻录工具等
this does burn kind of it effects the
这确实会燃烧它会影响到
colors of the image so right now we have
图像的颜色 所以现在我们有
it set to if we scroll down we have it
如果我们向下滚动 它将设置为我们有它
set to Dodge and and so Dodge is going
设置为道奇 这样道奇就会
to kind of lighten lighten up the colors
为了让颜色变得更明亮
in a certain area so maybe I could
在某个地区 所以也许我可以
whiten my teeth with this in a way but
在某种程度上用这个来美白我的牙齿
it's also getting my lips a little bit
它也让我的嘴唇变得有点
and the more you click it the more it
你点击的越多 它就越多
kind of applies it on top of the
某种程度上将其应用于
existing changes
现有更改
Bern is gonna be the opposite so if we
伯尔尼将是相反的 所以如果我们
select burn down here Bern kind of makes
选择在这里烧毁伯尔尼有点像
the colors more dark whatever's in that
颜色更深 不管里面是什么
area it makes it darker and more
它使它变得更暗更多
pronounced I can make my ear darker make
宣告我可以让我的耳朵变得更黑
my teeth darker so I kind of just bring
我的牙齿更黑了 所以我就带了
it kind of lightens up or darkens up the
它会让你的生活变得更明亮或更黑暗
area look at that you can like make look
你可以喜欢的地方看一看
like I haven't wearing makeup or
就像我没化过妆一样
something yeah
有些事是的
so that's Dodge and burn and there's
这就是道奇和伯恩 还有
different options right now we did we
现在我们做了不同的选择
did it adjusting the mid-tones we could
它调整了中间色调吗？我们可以
do the highlights which is gonna kind of
做一些亮点 这将是一种
darken anything part that has highlights
使任何有高光的部分变暗
I probably showed it on the teeth and we
我可能在牙齿上表现出来了 然后我们
control Z I could probably do teeth a
Control Z I大概可以做牙齿a
little bit more realistically with doing
在做某事时更现实一点
the highlights and if I adjust the size
高亮显示 如果我调整大小
of my brush I could probably achieve
我大概可以用我的画笔
some sort of a oh and then I need to
某种程度上的哦然后我需要
change it to Dodge instead of burn so
将其更改为Dodge而不是Burn 以便
we'll do Dodge here so it's gonna
我们会在这里做道奇 所以它会
lighten my teeth a little bit but it
让我的牙齿稍微亮一点 但它
keeps the colors so I kind of keeps some
保留了颜色 所以我保留了一些
of the natural looking colors of my
我看起来很自然的颜色
teeth but it kind of whitens it a little
牙齿 但会让牙齿变白一点
bit in there too so I don't know that's
我也不知道
super not realistic looking but this is
超级不现实的期待 但这是
probably not the tool you would use for
可能不是你会使用的工具
a teeth enhancement anyway or eyes I can
我可以做一个牙齿修复或者眼睛
lighten up the way my eyes are appearing
照亮我眼睛的样子
in here if I want to so anyway that's
如果我想的话 不管怎样
Dodge and burn and yeah that's really
道奇和燃烧 是的 这真的
what we're gonna cover today so play
我们今天要讲的内容
with smudge play with Dodge and burn but
用污迹玩道奇和燃烧
just kind of realize everything we've
意识到我们所做的一切
looked at so far the eraser that brush
我看了看 到目前为止
the pencil dodge burn the settings are
铅笔道奇烧伤的设置是
all very similar that they have it's all
都和他们的身体非常相似
these brush settings and then down below
这些画笔设置 然后在下面
it kind of has some specific settings
它有一些特殊的设置
more specific to that tool that we're
更具体地说 我们正在使用的工具
using hopefully you found this video
希望你能找到这段视频
informative go ahead and play with those
提供信息 继续玩那些
and the next video will look at some
下一个视频将介绍一些
more tools and continue learning about
更多工具 并继续学习